Guide to the Thomas W. Streeter Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photoreproductions, 1927-80; Series III; 2; (5 boxes)
  - INCLUDED IN BIBLIOGRAPHY OF TEXAS
    - No. 1635-1650, 1931-60, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 521)
    - No. 1651. Mexico (republic). Ejército. Ejército del Norte, 1957, 1960 (Box 66, Folder 522)
    - No. 1653. Mexico (republic). Presidente Interino, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 523)
  - OMITTED FROM BIBLIOGRAPHY OF TEXAS
    There are about seven imprints represented in each folder.
    - 1728-1829, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 524)
    - 1802-1841, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 525)
    - 1831-1832, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 526)
    - 1833, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 527)
    - 1834-1835, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 528)
    - 1836, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 529)
    - 1837-39, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 530)
    - 1840-42, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 531)
    - 1844-45, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 532)
    - 1846-47, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 533)
    - Undated, 1940-59 (Box 66, Folder 534)
- Background Material, 1861-1962; Series IV; 7.25; (18 boxes)
  Series IV, housed in Boxes 66a-83, is divided into Correspondence, General Subject Files, Files Given by Henry Raup Wagner, Files Given by Earl Vandale, Texas Maps, and Texas After 1845. Most of these subsections are arranged alphabetically.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - General notes on the correspondence files (Box 66a, Folder 535)
    - Individuals
      - Adams, Ramon F., 1956 (Box 66a, Folder 536)
      - Aldrich, Richard W., 1939 (Box 66a, Folder 537)
      - Allen, Albert H., 1947-53 (Box 66a, Folder 538-41)
      - Allen, Winnie, 1963-65 (Box 66a, Folder 542)
      - "B" general, 1950-57 (Box 66a, Folder 543)
      - Barker, Eugene C. and Amelia Williams, 1927-57 (Box 66a, Folder 544-46)
      - Burges, Richard F., 1927-45 (Box 66a, Folder 547)
      - "C" general, 1929-64 (Box 66a, Folder 548)
      - Caldwell, Frank, 1936-53 (Box 66a, Folder 549-53)
      - Castañeda, Carlos E., 1938-57 (Box 66a, Folder 554-60)
      - "E" general, 1935-49 (Box 66a, Folder 561)
      - Fisher, Harold W., 1938 (Box 66a, Folder 562)
      - Fitz Simon, Bishop Laurence J., 1946-55 (Box 66a, Folder 563)
      - "G" general, 1928-55 (Box 66a, Folder 564)
      - Green, Mrs. B. G., 1939-51 (Box 66a, Folder 565)
      - Guerra Escandón, Javier, 1951-52 (Box 66a, Folder 566-67)
      - Guerra Escandón, Javier, 1952-55 (Box 67, Folder 568-69)
      - "H" general, 1940-60 (Box 67, Folder 570)
      - Haley, J. Evetts, 1947-61 (Box 67, Folder 571)
      - Harrison, John W., 1954-55 (Box 67, Folder 572)
      - Heaney, Howell J., 1956-60 (Box 67, Folder 573-75)
      - Howard, William E., 1945 (Box 67, Folder 576)
      - Huson, Hobart, 1939-64 (Box 67, Folder 577)
      - "J" general, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 578)
      - Johnson, Crompton T., 1937-38 (Box 67, Folder 579)
      - Kemp, L. W., 1939-50 (Box 67, Folder 580)
      - Lockley, Fred, 1934 (Box 67, Folder 581)
      - "M" general, 1928-55 (Box 67, Folder 582)
      - Mary Agatha, Sister, 1940, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 583)
      - McLean, Malcolm D. and Margaret S., 1955-65, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 584-90)
      - McMurtie, Douglas C., 1929, 1931 (Box 67, Folder 591)
      - Maverick, Maury, 1954 (Box 67, Folder 592)
      - Milam, Coll J., 1951-52 (Box 67, Folder 593)
      - Moore, Ernest R., 1942-43 (Box 67, Folder 594)
      - Morrow, William H., 1956-61 (Box 68, Folder 595)
      - Moseley, J. A. R., 1946 (Box 68, Folder 596)
      - Muir, Andrew Frost, 1950-58 (Box 68, Folder 597-99)
      - "N, P" general, 1949-64 (Box 68, Folder 600)
      - "R" general, 1949-60 (Box 68, Folder 601)
      - Ratchford, Fannie E., 1937-46 (Box 68, Folder 602)
      - Richardson, Rupert N., 1926-64 (Box 68, Folder 603)
      - "S" general, 1928-58 (Box 68, Folder 604)
      - Shettles, E. L., 1928-38 (Box 68, Folder 605-06)
      - Spell, Lota M., 1953 (Box 68, Folder 607)
      - Sterns, Madeleine B., 1954 (Box 68, Folder 608)
      - Stevens, Mrs. A. F., 1928-29 (Box 68, Folder 609)
      - Vandale, Earl, 1935-52 (Box 68, Folder 610)
      - Vaught, Kathryn, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 611)
      - "W" general, 1927-65 (Box 68, Folder 612)
      - Wallace, Edward S., 1956-64 (Box 68, Folder 613-19)
      - Wharton, Clarence R., 1928-38 (Box 68, Folder 620-21)
      - Winkler, E. W., 1927-49 (Box 69, Folder 622-43)
      - Winkler, E. W., 1950-52, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 644-45)
      - Wrather, William E., 1932-42 (Box 70, Folder 646)
    - Institutions
      - Amarillo Public Library, 1950 (Box 70, Folder 647)
      - America-South-of-Us (bookseller), 1927 (Box 70, Folder 648)
      - Bancroft Library, 1928 (Box 70, Folder 649)
      - Baylor University, 1929-47 (Box 70, Folder 650)
      - Daughters of the Republic of Texas Library, 1954, 1956 (Box 70, Folder 651)
      - E. W. Nielson, 1929 (Box 70, Folder 652)
      - Edward Eberstadt (bookseller), 1927 (Box 70, Folder 653)
      - El Paseo Gem Shop, 1949-50 (Box 70, Folder 654)
      - "H" general, 1950, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 655)
      - Harris County Historical Society, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 656)
      - Henry E. Huntington Library, 1928-57 (Box 70, Folder 657-58)
      - Houston Public Library, 1940-54 (Box 70, Folder 659)
      - Library of Congress, 1929 (Box 70, Folder 660)
      - Massachusetts State Library, 1927 (Box 70, Folder 661)
      - Memphis State College, 1954-55 (Box 70, Folder 662)
      - "N" general, 1928-47 (Box 70, Folder 663)
      - National Archives, 1937-48 (Box 70, Folder 664-65)
      - Richard L. Schwartz Books, 1956 (Box 70, Folder 666)
      - Rosenbach Foundation, 1956 (Box 70, Folder 667)
      - Rosenberg Library, 1931-57 (Box 70, Folder 668-69)
      - "S" general, 1929, 1958 (Box 70, Folder 670)
      - San Antonio Public Library, 1940-53 (Box 70, Folder 671)
      - San Jacinto Museum of History, 1939-61 (Box 70, Folder 672-74)
      - Texas Heritage Foundation, Inc., 1957 (Box 70, Folder 675)
      - Texas State Historical Association, 1940-47 (Box 70, Folder 676-77)
      - Texas State Library, 1938-52 (Box 70, Folder 678-80)
      - Texas State Library, 153-59 (Box 71, Folder 681-82)
      - University of Texas Library, 1948-65 (Box 71, Folder 683-91)
      - W. H. Lowdermilk & Company, 1929 (Box 71, Folder 692)
      - Walter M. Hill Bookseller & Importer, 1929 (Box 71, Folder 693)
      - West Virginia Library Association, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 694)
      - Yale University Libraries, 1927-29 (Box 71, Folder 695)
  - GENERAL SUBJECT FILES
    - Streeter's organization of his files, 1955, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 696)
    - Austin, Stephen F.: writing desk and silhouette, 1944-60 (Box 71, Folder 697)
    - Beales, John Charles: land claims (Box 72, Folder 698)
    - Bibliographic entries for Texas items sold to Yale, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 699-700)
    - John Henry Brown Collection (purchased by Streeter)
      - Correspondence with Edward T. Moore, 1929-39 (Box 72, Folder 701)
      - Correspondence with Brown's descendants, 1935-48 (Box 72, Folder 702)
      - Lists of manuscripts, 1936, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 703)
    - Beauregard Bryan Collection (purchased by Streeter)
      - Correspondence, 1939-54 (Box 72, Folder 704-11)
      - Lists of material, 1940-44 (Box 72, Folder 712)
      - Lists of shipments and miscellaneous, 1940, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 713)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940 (Box 72, Folder 714)
    - Catalog of Texas Manuscripts, 1944-56, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 715)
    - Chihuahua al Pacifico Railroad, 1961-62 (Box 73, Folder 716)
    - Civil War: clippings regarding martial law in Texas, 1861-62, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 717)
    - Confederate songs, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 718)
    - Considerant, Victor, 1948, 1950 (Box 73, Folder 719)
    - Dienst, Alexander, 1936-37 (Box 73, Folder 720)
    - Exhibition of Streeter material
      - New York Public Library and Texas Centennial, 1936-37 (Box 73, Folder 721-26)
      - San Jacinto Museum of History, 1939, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 727-29)
      - University of Texas, 1936 (Box 74, Folder 730)
    - Falconer, Thomas: material regarding publication of manuscript, 1930 (Box 74, Folder 731)
    - Geiser, Samuel Wood, 1938-43 (Box 74, Folder 732)
    - Houston, Sam: silhouettes, 1936-50 (Box 74, Folder 733)
    - Houston Public Library, A Selected Bibliography of Texana, 1958 (Box 74, Folder 734)
    - Le clercq, P. Chrétien, Premier Establissement de la Foy, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 735)
    - Perry Fund: memorial for Henry Bryan Perry, 1957 (Box 74, Folder 736)
    - Pfeuffer Collection (purchased by Streeter), 1935-36 (Box 74, Folder 737)
    - Printing in Corpus Christi, 1959 (Box 74, Folder 738)
    - Railroads of Texas: imprints, 1836-71, 1944-49 (Box 74, Folder 739)
    - Roman Catholic Church in Texas, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 740)
    - Rutersville: city and college (Box 74, Folder 741-42)
    - Texas Association: clippings, 1941, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 743)
    - Texas land companies: letters to Alexander Dienst, 1902-21 (Box 75, Folder 744)
    - Texas land companies: clippings gathered by Alexander Dienst, 1903-11 (Box 75, Folder 745)
    - Texas lithographs, 1940-48 (Box 75, Folder 746)
    - Texas Santa Fé Expedition of 1841, 1935-36 (Box 75, Folder 747)
    - Travels in Texas: material regarding manuscript accounts, 1939-56 (Box 75, Folder 748)
    - Verein zum Schutz Deutscher Einwanderer, 1845, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 749)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 750)
  - FILES GIVEN BY HENRY RAUP WAGNER
    - Berlandier papers: descriptive list (Box 75, Folder 751-54)
    - Bexar Archives: printed materials, 1926, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 755)
    - Early Texas printing and newspapers (Box 75, Folder 756)
    - New Orleans newspapers: references to Texas in 1835, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 757)
    - Niles' Weekly Register (Baltimore) and other sources: references to Texas, 1939, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 758)
    - Texas imprints: books and broadsides at Yale and Library of Congress, 1928, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 759)
    - Maps of Texas, pre-1795, 1937, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 760-61)
  - FILES GIVEN BY EARL VANDALE
    - Baker, Mosely: typescripts of manuscripts on Houston and Texas (Box 75, Folder 762)
    - Ross, Reuben: typescript of manuscripts on the journey of Ross and Jas. Whitely in 1828, 1949, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 763)
  - TEXAS MAPS
    - Early notes by Elizabeth Greene, 1937, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 764)
    - Notes on maps showing Texas-Arkansas boundary, 1908, 1939, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 765-66)
    - Separate maps of Texas 1810-1845: bibliographic entries, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 767)
    - Bibliographic map entries and notes, 1795-1825 (Box 76, Folder 768-69)
    - Bibliographic map entries and notes, 1795-1825 (Box 77, Folder 770-76)
    - Bibliographic map entries entered but later omitted, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 777)
    - Bibliographic map entries entered but later omitted, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 778-81)
    - Checklist of Texas Maps, 1669-1845, 1938-41, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 782-83)
    - Checklist of Texas Maps, 1669-1845, 1938-41, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 784-86)
    - Checklist of Texas Maps, 1669-1845, 1938-41, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 787)
  - TEXAS AFTER 1845
    - Arrington, Alfred, Desperadoes of the Southwest, 1945 (Box 80, Folder 788)
    - Boundaries of Texas, 1946 (Box 80, Folder 789)
    - De Cordova map of Texas, 1928-42 (Box 80, Folder 790)
    - Northeast Texas: books about, 1945-46 (Box 80, Folder 791)
    - Smith, Abel, Reminiscences, 1876, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 792)
    - Société de Colonisation Européo-Américaine au Texas, 1938-50 (Box 80, Folder 793)
    - Texas Almanac, 1857-, 1951, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 794)
    - "Texas Biography, Autobiography, Poetry and Fiction, 1846-" (bibliography), 1944-54, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 795)
    - "Texas Biography, Autobiography, Poetry and Fiction, 1846-" (bibliography), 1944-54, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 796-797)
    - "Texas Catalog, 1846-1955" (bibliography), 1944-56, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 798-799)
    - "Texas Catalog, 1846-1955" (bibliography), 1944-56, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 800)
    - Texas Navy, 1937 (Box 83, Folder 801)
- Printer's Proofs for Part III, 1951-60; Series V; 1.25; (7 boxes)
  Printer's Proofs for Part III, housed in Boxes 84-90, are arranged in chronological order.
  - General notes, 1959 (Box 84, Folder 802)
    See also: Box 67, folder 573-75
  - Part III: main text
    - Galley, 1951 Jun (Box 84, Folder 803)
    - HJH Early Galley, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 804)
    - HJH Galley, 1959 Dec 28 (Box 86, Folder 805)
    - EB Galley, 1959 Dec 28 (Box 87, Folder 806)
  - "Introduction"
    - 1st Galley, [pre Jun 1960] (Box 88, Folder 807)
    - 2nd Galley, 1960 Jun 6 (Box 88, Folder 808)
    - 3rd Galley, 1960 Jun 6 (Box 88, Folder 809)
    - 4th Galley, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 810)
  - "Index"
    - EB Galley, 1960 Aug 5 (Box 88, Folder 811)
    - HJH Galley, 1960 Aug 13 (Box 88, Folder 812)
  - "Books Referred" and Appendices
    - HJH Galley, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 813)
    - Galleys, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 814)
  - Page Proofs, 1960 Sep 1 (Box 88, Folder 815-16)
  - Page Proofs, 1960 Sep 1 (Box 89, Folder 817-20)
  - Page Proofs, 1960 Sep 1 (Box 90, Folder 821-23)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 68, folder 546 (Box 91, Folder 824)
  - Box 68, folder 547 (Box 91, Folder 825)
  - Box 69, folder 566 (Box 91, Folder 826)
  - Box 69, folder 569 (Box 91, Folder 827)